<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Question>
<Subject>
What countries are the best to travel to?
</Subject>
<Content>
I really want to travel when I leave school!

Where in the states could I go?
Where in Europe?

Have you every traveled before? How long should I go for to each place? (I Have 1 year before collage!) 

&Also how much money would I need? So I can start saving now hehe

Thanks :)
I mean when I graduate & yes, college, sorry for the typo.
</Content>
</Question>
<ChosenAnswer>
Leave High School?  Not the smartest move to take off on a worldly adventure if you've never traveled before and you don't put where you would be traveling from.

In the United States?  Lots of places.  There are 50 of them, 48 located from Maine to Florida and California to Washington State and all in between.  There are 2 more located outside of the main continent with Alaska way to the north and Hawaii in the Pacific.  What do you like to do?  Big Cities like New York, Boston, Philadelphia on the East Coast.  Beaches and Disney of Florida or the Mid Atlantic cities of Atlanta, Savannah, Charleston.  The federal sites of Washington, DC.  Southern charm of Nashville, Birmingham, New Orleans or Charlotte. West Coast hot spots like Seattle, Portland, San Francisco, Los Angeles or San Diego.

Europe?  Just as numerous as the possibilities of the US.  Do you speak a foreign language? I could spend a year in Spain alone.  From Madrid to Seville to Barcelona an Valencia.  Bilboa on the north coast, Pamplona and the very famous Guernica.  A road trip to Lisbon and the Algarve in Portugal before a mountain escape in the Pyrenees and a stop in Andorra before heading over to France and Italy and Austria and Switzerland.

I've traveled to all of these places and could certainly tailor a trip to your needs based on budget, actual time allowed, your likes and dislikes.  Amount of time could be dependent on so many things.  Do you want to see all the sites or simply a few photos and on your way to the next place.  Does your budget limit you to how long you can stay in each place?  

You need a lot of money for hotels, airfare, seeing the sites, food, local transport - you name it but life costs.  Once you have a budget or an amount in the bank then you'll be able to figure out where you can go, for how long you can go and what you can do when you're there.

1 year before collage or college?  

Good luck.
</ChosenAnswer>
<Answers>
<Answer>
I recommend buying a single unlimited Europass and travelling anywhere in the EU your heart desires. You can't beat the price for what you get.
</Answer>
<Answer>
come to Africa.

Nigeria, a lovely country.

But where in nigeria?

Obudu cattle ranch.

More than a tourist centre.
</Answer>
</Answers>