<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Question>
<Subject>
How to convince my parents to let me get a Ball python?
</Subject>
<Content>
They don't know ANYTHING about Ball pythons. When I ask my mom she says she will never let a snake in her house. She has no experience with snakes and has never held one. I did all my research and am well prepared to keep one, I'm 14 by the way
</Content>
</Question>
<ChosenAnswer>
Lay some knowledge on them dude. Maybe if they see how much time and effort you've devoted to researching the animal they'll reconsider. Tell them it costs like 8 dollars a month (if even that much) to keep it fed. Be helpful around the house to show that even if you can't pay for it yourself that youre willing to work for it. Once you've buttered them up a bit try to get them to the pet store and ask one of the employees to handle the snake showing your mom how gentle and harmless they can be. Maybe even try to get your mom to hold it a bit. My wife was TERRIFIED of snakes when we first met, I introduced her to one out my baby corn snakes and she fell in love with it. Be persistent, but don't pester them about it cause that'll get you nowhere fast. Good luck!
</ChosenAnswer>
<Answers>
<Answer>
My general convince your parents to let you get a reptile advice:
1. Be responsible.  Do all your chores without being nagged, take care of any existing pets, keep your room clean, and so on.  Prove, to your parents' satisfaction, that you, not they, will be the one actually taking care of your new pet.
2. Save up, and research, so that you are ready for your new pet.
3. Bargain with them.  Offer to do extra chores, ask for your pet as a reward for good grades, something like that.
4. Play the sympathy card.  If you can find a pet at a shelter, or that a friend needs to get rid of because they're moving or whatever, you might be able to talk your parents into "giving it a good home" where you might not be able to talk them into buying a new pet.

On the fear angle--talk her into coming to the pet store with you.  Once you're there, ask if you can hold a ball python.  Once you're holding it, try to get her to touch/pet it...
</Answer>
</Answers>