<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Question>
<Subject>
does the bta have to be paid first to come to canada?
</Subject>
<Content>
</Content>
</Question>
<ChosenAnswer>
There is NO such thing as a BTA. That is a term invented by online romance scammers
http://www.country-couples.co.uk/datingtips/basic-travel-allowance-bta-dating-scam/
"Second only to flight money, the Basic Travel Allowance (BTA) is the scammers highest paying income.

Also known as the Personal Travel Allowance, Travellers Allowance Fee, Travellers Assistance Fund, Travellers Assurance Fund and numerous other forms of “I have to have wodges of your cash or they won’t let me fly”.

Let’s get this over with now … THERE IS NO SUCH THING any more, anywhere, it’s an online dating scam."


http://www.romancescam.com/forum/viewtopic.php?t=7231
"THERE IS NO SUCH THING AS BASIC TRAVEL ALLOWANCE!!

Please remember: there is NO such thing. There is NO such requirement, in any country of the world. This is an invention of the scammers. "


A single call to CIC will confirm there is NO such thing as a BTA to Canada and anyone asking for this is a scammer http://www.cic.gc.ca/english/contacts/index.asp

Just pray that you have not ever given this criminal enough information for your identity to be stolen - your full name, birthdate, home address, etc or that you were not conned into sending money. This person is not coming to visit you - the whole point of this scam is to gain your trust enough to steal your money and identity

Contact the Anti-Fraud Centre to report this http://www.antifraudcentre-centreantifraude.ca/english/home-eng.html
</ChosenAnswer>
<Answers>
<Answer>
No. BTA only exists in the mind of SCAMMERS.

100% SCAM. cut of all contact and tighten up your PC security.
</Answer>
<Answer>
There is no such thing as a BTA or "Basic Travel Allowance"-this is 100% a scam-as the first poster said,cut off any and all contact with this person-they are NOT who or what they are claiming to be.The below site from the US government verifies this-it's the same for Canada ,too.....


http://nigeria.usembassy.gov/scams.html
</Answer>
</Answers>
