<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Question>
<Subject>
What sort of Hotel could I expect to find in New Delhi/Agra/Varanasi for rs500 per night?
</Subject>
<Content>
Hey guys. I'm looking to visit India with some mates at the beginning of February next year and I am wandering what standard of accommodation we could get for Rs 500 per person per night. There would be four of us so we would probably be looking at 2 twin rooms for Rs1000, close to the centre of these cities. This would be on a walk-in basis as we want to have the freedom of finding a place that looks good (Not relying on pictures from the internet) and is in a spot we like. Thanks in advance for sharing your experience!
Sorry, almost forgot to ask - Would it be cheaper to walk-in to these hotels rather than pre book?
</Content>
</Question>
<ChosenAnswer>
In Delhi I'd recommend Ajay Guesthouse. Travelled to Delhi twice and stayed there twice. Rooms start from 500 per double. Those ones are quite small. Must say, in Delhi it's hard to get good price/quality rating. I have found this hotel in the Lonely Planet guide. It's in an area starting with a P, many tourist hotels there and the location is very nice. But in general, Delhi is the hardest place to find a nice clean hotel for that price. 

In Varanasi I don't know. I've stayed in a more expensive hotel there, but you can check some travelguides or tripadvisor? Also, while travelling ask people where they've been and if they have any hotel recommendations. 

In Agra I've stayed in a place fellow travellers recommended, they found it in the Rough Guide. It was nice and close to the Taj. It was quite easy to find something. (Dont stay in Agra too long. One night is enough!) There were many hotels there. Ive paid 500 for a double room there and it was fine and clean. 

Good luck, enjoy your time!
</ChosenAnswer>
<Answers>
<Answer>
You may find a normal budget hotel for Rs 1000 per night in the cities you mentioned, the links below may help you to find good hotels in Delhi and Agra.

http://www.goldentriangleindia.com/delhi/hotels-in-delhi.html
</Answer>
<Answer>
To Stay in delhi - Hotel Aster Inn is best to stay in delhi. it is in karol bagh. some beautiful locations like close to Karol Bagh Shopping Market, Presidential Palace, and Birla Mandir Temple and Connaught Place and Jantar Mantar are near to it.

TO Stay in Agra -Hotel Atithi and Aditya Palace is perfect for you. it is centrally situated.

To Stay in Varanasi - Sandeep Hotel is you choice...
</Answer>
</Answers>
