<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Question>
<Subject>
are my two cats fighting or playing? how rough is too rough? help!?
</Subject>
<Content>
i have a 1 and a half year old male neutered cat and a new 2 month old spayed female kitten. the first night i brought her home i did the sniffing under the door thing and left it at that. the next day i let her out of the bedroom so they could check each other out, and the kitten hissed twice within the first 20 minutes of meeting each other and now she no longer hisses and they have been playing(chasing each other up and down the hall, rolling around on the ground and pawing at each other). only once it looked like my male cat was biting at her neck and then her stomach and she was meowing fairly loud and hissed once then he backed off and now they are fine. were they roughhouse playing? or were they actually fighting? he has been "biting" at her neck and stomach previously while they play without her meowing or anything so im wondering if he went a little to far that one time. any answers help!!!!!!
</Content>
</Question>
<ChosenAnswer>
you did not leave the new kitten in the room long enough. you need to do that for a least a week, or else this type of territorial fighting will happen.
giving the new kitten her own small territory will help her to feel safe and will give her a place to go to when scared.
right now, your male is fighting off an intruder, and he feels that all of the house is his.
put her back in the room, and keep the door closed for a week. then let her out for ten minutes. make it fifteen the next day, then twenty, and so on.

this will do two things; the new kitten will rub her cheek on the furniture in her room, making it her territory. she will start to calm down and feel safe - you can bet she doesn't now. she knows she is invading someone else's territory, but can't help it, and has no where to go.
she will be able to sleep without being afraid.

as well, your male will be able to see that his territory is not threatened. when the door opens, he will get that the one room is hers, and he will be OK with that. the territory thing will be solved.

your male is hurting her to put her in her place - biting her scruff is dominance and biting the belly is a move cats use when hunting - to pull the guts out of their prey.
this is not good.

give them time to set up their territories, and once you bring the new kitten out, pay a lot of attention to the male. you have brought someone else into his territory, and he needs to be reminded that you still love him, and support his claim to his space.
that will help to reassure him, and he will be less aggressive with her.

when they play fight, they don't hiss. if they hiss, they are not playing. if they bite, and one cries, you must separate them, and you must keep an eye on them.
hissing is OK, unless they start to fight. if that happens, separate them, and give them time apart. putting the girl in her territory will make her feel less afraid, and she will relax.

good luck!
</ChosenAnswer>
<Answers>
<Answer>
A hiss is basically a "get the f*ck away" sound. It means they've gone too far. When they start bleeding that means they're really fighting. If they're going kinda slow and like fake biting (not biting as hard as they can), and fake scratching (not hitting as hard as they can with their paws) then they're playing.
</Answer>
<Answer>
I have two cats, and at first they hissed at each other because cats are very territorial, but now they do fight and play. The difference is when the cat hisses, that means they are annoyed and they want the other cat to go away. That means they are fighting. When they are just jumping at each other and their tails are wagging that means that they are playing. I can see how you get confused though. :)
</Answer>
</Answers>