<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Question>
<Subject>
which one out of these makes the best pet?
</Subject>
<Content>
a degu, a rat, a mouse, a hamster or a guinea pig? and why is the one a better pet?
</Content>
</Question>
<ChosenAnswer>
Get a guinea pig. I have a hamster, and mice and rats like to escape. The Guinea pig is better because its a lot larger than a hamster, rat, mouse, or degu. So if you lose him, he is easier to find, because smaller rodents just LOVE to escape from their cages. So my opinion is Guinea pigs. (plus they dont stink that bad)
</ChosenAnswer>
<Answers>
<Answer>
Depends on what you want in a pet, to be honest. Also depends on the space you have, how much time you can handle the pet, how much money you can spend, etc.

I've had experience with all of those pets except Degus. My favorite would have to be the rat. They're incredibly social, highly trainable, and very clean. Mine learned to "go to the bathroom" only in their cages and loved to ride on my shoulder or hang out in my hoodie pouch. The only downside is they should be kept in pairs or trios and require a pretty large habitat. That means expense, space, and they require weekly cage cleaning.

My second favorite would have to be the Guinea Pig - not quite as social with people as rats (at least mine wasn't) but more so than most hamsters or mice. Again, pairs or trios and pretty big living space. They, too, need weekly cage cleaning and can cost quite a bit.

I could handle my mice, but they where skittish and preferred their cage. I've never met a hamster that didn't bite me. Never had/handled a Degu.
</Answer>
<Answer>
Get a guinea pig.  We have two.  They are social and like to be handled.  You have to have two because they don't do well alone.  Make certain you get two females.  Two males can fight and you definitely don't want babies!!

Guinea pigs (also called cavies) are gentle creatures and are awake during the day and sleep at night.  They will whistle when they hear you as an encouragement for you to give them a treat like leaf lettuce.

They love leaf or romaine lettuce and tomatos, celery, cucumbers, carrots.  Don't feed them broccoli, cauliflower, garlic, onions, head lettuce ....they are all too difficult for them to digest.  Also they can't eat potatos, they are toxic for them.

If you keep the cage clean they don't smell and you can buy spray on cleaser for them, just massage it into their coat and groom them.
</Answer>
</Answers>