<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Question>
<Subject>
Was the San Francisco Bay Area mostly Caucasian back in the early 1970s?
</Subject>
<Content>
</Content>
</Question>
<ChosenAnswer>
No.  There has been a large Asian presence in the SF Bay Area for a long time--the Chinatown here was the largest population of chinese outside of China, there were lots of Japanese who'd been displaced during WWII.  The whole Western Addition and a large portion of the Haight was black.  The Mission was basically latin-american.  As the southeast asians and philipinos came over, they added to the cultures.  So, the Bay Area has been fairly mixed ethnically for a long time--caucasians may have seemed to be a large populous but that's because most tourists back then were caucasian and many of the hippies were caucasians so that's who the photographers took pictures of.  The other ethicities weren't well represented in politics yet--or rather, they were just breaking the color barrier in the 70's due largely to the more open-minded hippy generation.  Marin County was predominantly caucasian and many of the expanding outer east bay areas started out as white suburbs.
</ChosenAnswer>
<Answers>
<Answer>
It was not so long after Civil Rights laws against discrimination started to have an impact. You never saw black MUNI drivers, Asian police, Latino politicians until then. It was an evolution.

Many illegals were not counted in the population until the mid-80s. We did not have big percent of Chinese migration until the mid 90s. We had fewer people running across the Mexican border then. We had fewer social benefits at that time for people so many immigrants were not counted. Only Caucasians had any political power, corporate presence or owned businesses except for Mom and Pop stores in some neighborhoods. San Francisco was settled in the 19th and 20th century by mainly European immigrants except for some Asian workers who were manual laborers. There has always been a Mexican-American cultural influence since Calif was owned by Mexico.

We had a larger black population in the 70s than we have now but they did not have any power until Willie Brown was elected. San Francisco was always progressive and welcoming and tolerant to all kinds of people historically. The counties outside San Francisco were more white than San Francisco in the 70s.

EDIT: My memory may not be good so you might get a more accurate answer from someone else who remembers the time.
</Answer>
</Answers>