<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Question>
<Subject>
why does my baby king snake refuse to eat?
</Subject>
<Content>
i have a baby eastern king snake. i have tried EVERYTHING i can to get him to eat but he refuses. he has a great environment, with water and lots of hiding places and a heat lamp. as far as i know, everything is as good as it can be where his aquarium is concerned. according to the vet, he is healthy and looks good. he has been going to the bathroom like he should. (i know that snakes that have problems going to the bathroom won't eat.) he has been drinking water (i am pretty sure he has been drinking it out of his bowl, but also i have been feeding him water and he doesn't ever give me a problem with that - i just stick his head near the water and he sucks it down.) i handle him every few days. he is feisty, as most king snakes are, but he is a very nice little guy - he never tries to bite or anything. i just love him to death. i don't know why he won't eat though! i have tried feeding him 5 or 6 live pinkies and 4 or 5 frozen (thawed) pinkies. i have never tried feeding him a pinky that was bigger around than he is. i have tried putting him in a small container and putting him in a dark place for an hour or so and he won't touch the pinky. he crawls on top of them but does not try to eat them. he doesn't seem to know that they are food. i have tried "braining" both live and dead pinkies, and bloodying them up to get his attention, but he doesn't care. i have tried dipping both live and thawed pinkies in tuna juice, and in used gerbil bedding. i have bought some long reptile feeding tweezers and have tried holding the pinky in front of the snake's face. he wont even try to bite. i am very discouraged and sad and i don't know what to do. he hasn't eaten in an entire month.
i've only tried to feed him one at a time. he's just a tiny baby, about the width of a pencil. do babies this small hibernate?
</Content>
</Question>
<ChosenAnswer>
When you feed him how many pinkies do you feed him? If you feed him too many he could just not be hungry. If he doesn't seem interested in them at all I would say he's just not hungry. My boyfriend has one and when she's hungry she attacks the pinkie right away. They can smell it so i'm sure he knows what it is and just don't want it. Remember snakes can go awhile without eating. 
In the winter, they will usually go deep underground and enter a hibernation-like state called brumation, which is characterized by a slowed metabolism and reduced activity. King snakes sometimes stop eating, particularly during the cooler part of the year. They have a natural instinct to hibernate. If the snake is not pregnant or shedding, and its enclosure is properly equipped, a loss of appetite probably signals a beginning of hibernation. Hibernation is natural, and a necessity for snakes that are going to be bred. Another thing that can cause a king snake to stop eating is shedding. You can tell when your king snake is about to shed, because its eyes will get milky looking. Its body will be dull looking, too. In a few days the snake will begin to shed its skin. For example, some snakes will routinely go off their food in both the summer and winter, feeding mainly in spring and fall. It's natural and so long as you don't see any serious deterioration in their health is nothing to worry about.You see, some snakes for no obvious reason will simply go off their food. They're fit and healthy and their care is suitable.


hope this helped.
</ChosenAnswer>
<Answers>
<Answer>
That's why it's good to have a python! It's twice my size and eats a rabbit once a month.
</Answer>
</Answers>