<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Question>
<Subject>
Fostering 6 week old kittens and HATING IT! Need Advice!?
</Subject>
<Content>
I wanted to volunteer and help animals, and decided to try fostering kittens. This is my first experience and I have two six week old kittens right now and am at my wits end. I do not want to have to bring them back before they are eight weeks old but they are ruining my apartment. They track poop everywhere (most disgustingly my bed....), and am constantly trying to climb up everything, including my bare legs! My legs and hands are just full of scratches. I realize they are young and that cats do climb, but this is just ridiculous. My apartment also smells repulsive even though I am cleaning out their litter box at least once a day if not twice. Any suggestions and helpful hints to make this a more positive experience would be extremely appreciated.
</Content>
</Question>
<ChosenAnswer>
That's kind of the way it goes..lol.  Limit them to one room with easy to clean flooring.  If you have limited options, try the bathroom.  Make sure there are plenty of litter boxes that are cleaned often.  Depending on the batch of kittens, I will often have as many as one per kitten.  They can produce a lot of waste and even scooping twice a day they can get messy.  For some reason it takes them awhile to learn not to step in poop.  Also if they have diarrhea, check in with your foster coordinator.  They made need medication or deworming or something.

They are testing out their claws and teeth.  To some degree you can/should help teach them not to use their teeth and claws inappropriately.  But in the meantime, highly recommend jeans and long sleeves anytime you'll be interacting with the kittens.

Then take care of yourself.  Get plenty of sleep and make sure you take time out to do some things you enjoy.  Try visiting the kittens a few times a day for short periods of time.  Try to go in there with the right frame of mind and enjoy them for what they are.  If you still don't enjoy the kittens, see what other opportunities are available.  They may need foster homes for adult cats in different situations.. sick, recovering from surgery, need a little socialization, etc.  I find the adults are much easier.  Generally they're not clawing and biting, they don't make nearly as much mess, they don't need nearly as much litterbox scooping, etc :)
</ChosenAnswer>
<Answers>
<Answer>
Decide volunteering is not your thing and give them back!
And do more research before you agree next time ;-)
</Answer>
<Answer>
Take the kittens back to the shelter. Maybe do volunteer work at the humane society, walk dogs, groom the animals etc.
</Answer>
</Answers>