<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Question>
<Subject>
I'm American and I am going to the UK for the first time, what should I expect?
</Subject>
<Content>
I just need to talk to an another american who has gone to the UK before so that I know what expect when arriving at the airport and with going through visa process and everything. do you get your visitors visa immediately at the airport? I was told that americans automatically get a six months visitors visa. do you have to go through a medical exam right away? drug test? blood test? or do i just show them passport and walk through the gates? i have talked to some people that say that a medical exam is an invasion of privacy and other say its a routine thing when entering another country.
I honestly have no idea what to expect or prepare for and calling in to get professional advice from either of the embassies costs by the minute- which I really don't have the money for. 
I'm really worried cause I have no idea who to talk to and want everything to go smoothly.
</Content>
</Question>
<ChosenAnswer>
</ChosenAnswer>
<Answers>
<Answer>
An American passport should get you right into the country, there is no need for a VISA, for six months.  There is no medical exam or blood test or others like that.  You do not need to call the embassies to get professional advice.

http://travel.state.gov/travel/cis_pa_tw/cis/cis_1052.html

Above is the link to the Department of State travel website, which will give you all the info that you need, including passport information.  It is free.
</Answer>
<Answer>
I never stayed more than two weeks at a time when I visited the U.K.  You should be fine with just a passport, unless you're staying longer than six months.  You should double check with the necessary embassy before you leave though.  I am not sure how well you planned this trip.

You'll have a great time, so no worries there.  I visited London, Edinburgh, and St. Andrews so far, and I was treated very well and with great kindness.  Just treat everyone else as you would want to be treated, and you'll be fine.  That tactic never failed me.
</Answer>
</Answers>