<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Question>
<Subject>
True or false: being a young New Zealander means having no future?
</Subject>
<Content>
There are no jobs in this country. I'm just trying to make up my mind whether I should move to Australia or seek work in the sex industry.

Is there a future for our nation's youth?
@Ryan B,
I'm two years into an undergraduate degree. Everybody I know at university intends to stay at uni for as long as possible until there are actually jobs available. Everybody seems to flee this country and move overseas, to Australia, etc. There's obviously a reason for that (lack of employment, low incomes, etc.)

Your answer doesn't do anything but remind me that I'm going to be $25,000 in debt by the time I'm 22. So, thanks.
@W.a.b.b.y,
I really like you're answer. it's very logical. I've also considered becoming a teacher, but it's not a job I'm cut out for.

I also wish I'd applied for a scholarship. I didn't think I'd be awarded one, but I received the Dux Litterarum award at high school, so my chances were probably better than I thought they were. Obviously I'm still completely stupid though. I mean, I wasn't smart enough to apply for a scholarship.

And yes, I am being melodramatic. Lol. 
@Hatmanone,
*gasps* So I wouldn't make a good prostitute? Are you saying I'm bad in bed? How would you know?
Joking.

Your answer is very sweet, but I'm not compassionate towards teenage high school students. 
</Content>
</Question>
<ChosenAnswer>
A little mellow dramatic? 

In my opinion, far too many people are at university studying worthless degrees. Yes things like philosophy and fashion design are interesting, but how many jobs are out there for someone with these qualifications? I'm studying to be a teacher, so I know that there will definitely be jobs out there when I'm done. I may have to live somewhere rural or in Auckland, but at least I can be pretty sure I'll be employable. I've also got a bachelors degree so I can go back and do further study or take a different profession.

I also know that you don't get paid that much more in Australia than you do here. And it's not all about how much you earn, cost of living is much higher in many cities in Australia. Try living in Sydney on a teacher's salary, then compare it to somewhere like Central Otago. You also have to put up with all the annoying accents in Australia.

It's probably not a wise idea to keep studying and having a massive student loan. At the moment there's no interest, but that'll probably change. And they'll probably add interest to what you've already racked up. And they're working towards being able to extradite people who have left the country to avoid paying it back. At the moment if you move overseas you can only come back to New Zealand for a short amount of time before they'll force you cough up. And all that time you're overseas you'll be racking up interest. I wouldn't like not having the option to return to NZ.

I guess I'm extremely fortunate that I received a scholarship which paid about 800f my course fees through my degree. But I worked hard and I'm still working hard. There are far too many lazy people out there who think that they can sit around a job will fall in their lap. 

My 2c.

....
</ChosenAnswer>
<Answers>
<Answer>
Get an education! I'm doing fine.
</Answer>
<Answer>
Whilst youth jobs are thin on the ground, don't assume it's better in Oz. People have been fleeing this country at roughly a plane load per week for the past 20+ years, so it's not anything new. 

It depends on what you hunger for. 700f jobs aren't advertised. That means making yourself known; that means networking.
</Answer>
</Answers>