<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Question>
<Subject>
EPM, Anyone Dealt with it? Might be something different?
</Subject>
<Content>
I have the opportunity to pick up a super nice 6 year old for free. He's not lame, but he's been having issues. 

Here's what the owner has said:
I have a 5 year old that lost all of his cheek muscle on the right side about 3-4 months ago.  I chalked it up to possible nerve damage, because this is what the vet thought and the other cheek muscle was fine and he had no theeth problems.  So I sent him to the trainers the first of September to be started on the barrels.  I got him back the first of the month and he had lost some weight but attributed that to be worked everyday (I expected him to drop some).  He is now losing the cheek muscle on the left side of his face and seems to be dropping weight by the day.  Had him to a dentist yesterday and there is no teeth problems.  He can eat all his feed and doesn't drop any, but cannot eat hay from lack of muscle to chew it.  He is gant looking in his flank area and is losing topline muscle.  The only neurological sign that he shows is that he barely drags his toes and sometimes has trouble with his right lead.

The horse I had posted about a couple weeks ago with the atrophied cheek muscles is down to his last resort for life.  I CANNOT afford to treat whatever is wrong with him.  NO, I have not done an EPM test but have done an extensive blood panel and my vet did a neurological physical exam.  We elected to not do the EPM test because there was NO neurological signs.  He is still showing no signs other than the weight loss, and some muscle atrophy.  He eats all of his grain but it just takes him a while to get it chewed because of the lack of muscle in his jaws.


So I might get the horse and see what I can do. I will be getting with my vet first and if I do get him, have the spinal fluid test done for EPM and a titer test. Will be getting a copy of the blood results the owner has already ran as well. 

My other theory would be wobblers. I'll be having my equine chiro/acupuncturist out to do some work as well if I do get him....

So any ideas? Think I should do it?
Arby, 

Horse is out of state and not local. Owner is willing to meet me half way with him. 

I will be calling my vet and chiro about him. Worse comes to worse, I'm out of the $$ and have to put him down anyway or have a pretty pasture ornament. He's still rideable currently and not having many issues under saddle. 

This is a horse that I otherwise wouldn't be able to afford and even if I spend 2K and treatment I come out ahead of his purchase price.
I posted what the owner as said in paragraph 2 & 3, that is not me to clarify. She is the one that can't afford to do anything else for him in case he doesn't recover fully. 

He can eat grain and I already have a feed regimen in my head for the guy since he can't eat regular hay. I don't think it will be hard to keep his weight up so long as he can eat the grain.

I am not going to go pick up a horse I can't afford. I am willing to pull the EPM test and treat. The owner is the one who is unable. I will also be having my other vet up who's a chiro & acupuncturist to evaluate him for wobblers.

July is when he started to exhibit slight symptoms and the owner and vet originally thought it was just some nerve damage from something in the pasture with no visible injury. He's only exhibited weight loss and some muscle atrophy, with the slight toe drag and a bit of trouble with the right lead (which could or couldn't be related).

The horse is not in pain. He's not starving. He's dropping we
The horse is not in pain. He's not starving. He's dropping weight, but most of that came from being at the trainers and being ridden hard for 60 days. He's not putting it back on.

I know that I have the possibility of treating him and still having to put him down. At the same time I do know people who have had horses come back successfully after EPM. I know this is going to be expensive. I'm willing to give it a shot. 

Gallop, I've already read that whole site and been reading through research articles from the research colleges as well. Looked at studies, treatment options and such. I will have the EPM test done before treating. The chiro/acupuncturist will be there to evaluate the horse for wobblers which is often caused by spinal compression and can be confused with EPM. If that is the case then acupuncture isn't going to hurt him. It's actually one of the alternative therapies for EPM
</Content>
</Question>
<ChosenAnswer>
I think it is wonderfully responsible that you are going into this rescue eyes open and are getting the opinions of qualified professionals (and a bunch of Yahoos) before you decide to take this horse on.  I do think some Y!A users need to work on their reading comprehension as I can't comprehend how taking a horse in as a rescue and getting it qualified medical treatment is abuse.  

Worst case scenario you fall in love and after spending thousands of dollars you have to put the horse down.  Is that something you are up for?  If so go for it and I'll give you all the moral support I can as you figure out what is up.  It is heartbreaking to try to bring a horse back and then have to put it down, but some horses are worth the risk.  If you feel this guy is worth it then I hope your vet can figure things out. 

As to EPM like Shee said being in MI we've had to deal with it.  Pretty much every large stable has here.  Our first diagnosed EPM horse was back when there was no treatment in the US and only an experimental chicken feed additive in Canada. We hauled the horse to Windsor and got him  treated there.  

That horse returned to racing and we didn't notice much difference.  We've had a few since then, but none since our race horses began wintering in Florida.  I have no idea if that is related or farmers are doing a better job of clearing out opossums now because they know opossums are carriers, but we haven't had an EPM horse in at least 10 years.

I can say all of our EPM horses were treated early when they were showing mild signs like Shee gave and all returned to racing.  One horse even got his lifetime mark after being treated for EPM.  We've always liked big long trotters that do better on mile tracks then 1/2 mile.  The only difference we noticed is that the EPM horses seemed to do worse on the smaller tracks after.  It might just be coincidence or the fact those great big trotters with those extremely long backs lost a bit of fine coordination to get those gangly bodies around those tighter turns.  I don't know.  

MSU does a lot of EPM studies because of how common it is here.  You may want to see if you can get in touch with their EPM group and get this guy in a study.  I know they did lab work showing that Strongid C used daily could help  prevent EPM.  I believe they have a real study testing the lab work in real world situations now, but it may be sometime before those results are released.  

Another thought with this being a mosquito season from hell could it be West Nile?  West Nile can cause EPM like symptoms and doesn't always include a fever.  

Let us know what you decide to do.  You hate to see talent get wasted, but honestly I don't think I could take in a horse right now these issues.
</ChosenAnswer>
<Answers>
<Answer>
Personally I think you should just keep on walking by.  

You should have you chiro out before you decide if you want this horse or not.  If you have a good repoire (which I'm sure you do) with them, they should be honest on if this horse is fixable to any degree... not really sure what you want to do with him...  

Even if you can figure out what is wrong with this poor poneh, there is always the chance for remission and then relapse so you may have to do deal with again in the future.

So all in all, put the money up front before taking on this horse.  A few hundred out of pocket now will possibly save you thousands once the horse is in your name.
</Answer>
<Answer>
Could he have had a blow to the head causing this atrophy?  Or a difficult birth?  Was it always like this?  Or has it occurred since birth.

I also wonder if he might have had a slight stroke?  

I think if you cannot afford to get him treated that you should not consider him as a prospect.  Who knows what the future might hold, and it might be expensive?
</Answer>
</Answers>