<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Question>
<Subject>
This is about my farrier, girls. That's why I'm posting here! Help?
</Subject>
<Content>
I posted this in singles and dating too, so I've just copied and pasted.



Well, I'll try to make this short.
I have known this guy for a long time, but we've never been good friends or anything. He is my farrier (shoes my horses feet) so I am technically a client if you want to view it that way.
Well, almost two weeks ago he came out and did my horses feet and was SO flirty. He always hugs me when he comes, but he gave me at least 5 tight, long, back rubbing hugs while he was there. We were also just talking about my horse's crappy feet and he mentioned. "Well, if you ever just want to see me I'll come out and look him over and then we can grab a coffee after."
That has NEVER happened before so I was kinda realizing at that point that he was a little interested. Right??
Anyway, so he ended up leaving one nail out of my horses foot(I've never heard of a farrier doing this) and telling me to call him in a few days(first it was a week, then it was a few days lol) and he'd come back out and put it in. He told me to remember to call like 3 times before he left.
So, I waited a week to call because I was busy and I wanted to have him come out on a day when I am more available in case we were to hang out after ;)
Anyway, so that was 2 days ago that I called and left a message, but he still hasn't called back yet.
I don't know if I should call him again tomorrow or not?
I know a lot of people say to wait until he calls you, but it's different because I'm a client and technically that's all I am at this point.
On the other hand though, if I'm a client he should really of called back by now because you don't leave a customer hanging.
He didn't have my number either because this was the first time I've called HIM instead of his dad. It's a father and son business.

Anyway, I would appreciate ANY insight on this at all.
Thank you for reading if you did! :)
Ok, well as far as him being a bad farrier for leaving a nail out - That is not the case, they are extremely well known farriers in the area. I would be a lot more concerned if the shoe fell off because it was missing one lousy nail.
The reason he said he didn't put that nail in was because he "didn't want to risk it" with my horse's horrible feet. This is about the fourth time they've done my horse's feet because I just switched back to them. The only reason I switched away from them in the first place is because my good friend who apprenticed with them was starting out on his own. However, he left my horse without a shoe for TWO WEEKS(now that's what I call a crap farrier). Which, I might add is the same foot that keeps crumbling with the nails.
So, obviously I switched back to these guys.
Ok, calm down, it's not like he's some stranger that came up and groped me lol. I've known the guy for about 10 years. I am 21, so yeah we were both kids when we knew each other! He is a few years older than me.
And yes, I do like him.
To answer Barry White, yes that did occur to me :) I hope that is all he's waiting for. On the other hand, he could very easily just call me and say hey I'm busy right now, I'll call you when I can come out.

And as far as scheduled visits go, I have no idea. I've never done that before though either. It's always just "Okay, they're feet need to be done, better call the farrier." And they usually come out within a few days.
</Content>
</Question>
<ChosenAnswer>
He will call you back Im sure! Sounds like He really likes you.. But you need to ask yourself do you feel the same way? would You like going for *coffee* with him? or is he Not your type? Or are you undecided? If i were you I would Go... I would say if he does not call you back by friday call him again he could be playing hard to get? I think he left the Nail out of the shoe as a excuse to come back and see you hey he may be your Prince charming.. 
Edit... I really dont think Your horse Is in danger Of being hurt With one Nail missing.. I have seen horses Loose Nails On there Own And do just fine with ONE nail gone Now if he had left out 2 or 3 I would be wondering to... I really do belive he left the nail out becuse of the horses Hoof condition and Its a added bonus he would get to see her again
When I was Younger In my early 20s My farrier was A hottie named Joby..( for those who don't Know I AM A GIRL read my Bio on my Page) dumb as a post about everything But horses.. He was In his 30s divorced and Had 2 kids.. but we both flirted Horribly with each other.. but neither one of us took the chance and Asked to other on a date. :( sorta wonder what it would have been like? But That was Years ago. He had this Habit of telling you Everything.. Well one day he said to me You know i don't wear Underwear as he was bent over Working on my Mares Right front hoof.. and I was Like Ummmm okay??? Im glad his butt was facing me so he couldn't see my red face I think my Mare was even laughing.. Well 6 weeks Later when he came back out He was again working on my mares front Foot and I looked Down and Yeah he had Wholes In his pants In the wrong places I bust out Laughing and He was like what??? I was like Ummmm i can see your ass cheeks...he was like Oops did i forget my Underwear??? that was a strange way to flirt.. but i guss it was his way... But like i said nothing ever came of It.. the next time I saw him He had told Me he had To get married to a girl Who he worked with becuse he knocked Her Up.. I was heartbroken.. but then realized He was not the Guy for me..
</ChosenAnswer>
<Answers>
<Answer>
Wow he does sound interested in you, my farrier never gives me hugs like that (probably a good thing as he has a wife and 2 kids) anyway, I find that they can be very busy so I would wait a week lo9nger and if still no reply give him a call but don’t leave a message so you don’t have to necessarily wait for him to call.
</Answer>
<Answer>
From the point of view of a business, and client/operator relationships, he's doing a really shitty job. Leaving nails out so you'll call and have him come back out later? Cute or not, I'd call a different bloke because he's doing a sub-par job at something he needs to be doing his best at, whether he's flirting or trying to ask you out or not, he ought to put quality first. This is, after all, his business, and if he wants you to remain a customer why on earth is he doing shoddy work?
</Answer>
</Answers>