<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Question>
<Subject>
What would you get if you cross a sussex male and a silkie female?
</Subject>
<Content>
i had a sussex male and a pekin female i bought 2 silkies what would the sussex female and the silkie females would make ?if you had any pics of your hens i would like to see them to compare them to mine thanks?
</Content>
</Question>
<ChosenAnswer>
A Sussex crossed with Silkie would make a crossbred *mutt* chicken.  There are a lot of genetics at play between a Sussex and Silkie, so the offspring would vary in appearance. You don't say what color Silkie or Sussex you are dealing with so I can't say what color your chicks would be likely to be.  However, I can say what features they would/could have.

Feather Type. Silkies have hookless feathers. Sussexs have soft feathers.  All offspring from this cross will have soft feathers, as hookless feathers are a recessive gene.

Skin Color: Silkies have black skin color, which is dominate.  Sussex have White Skin which could be recessive or dominate.  Either way rec. and dom. white genes dilute the black gene. Skin will be darker but lighter then the Silkies.

Beards/Muffs: If your Silkie has a beard/muff the offspring could have a beard as well, as these genes are incomplete dominate.  

Feathered Feet/Shanks- Chicks could have feathered feet/shanks as this is also incomplete dominate.

Crest: Chicks could also develop a small crest due to this being another incomplete dominate gene.

Comb Type: Silkies have walnut combs which is actually genetically two comb types (Rose and Pea) single is also there, but is recessive.  So crossed to a Sussex you could get a walnut, pea, rose, or single combed bird. 

Five Toes: Silkies have five toes. Sussex have four toes.  Crossed together (five toes is incompletely dominate) chicks could develop to have an fifth toe on both, or even one foot. 

Silkie crosses are great birds, and very neat looking.  Hens make excellent mothers as they are bigger, can see better, and are smarter the Silkies.

Best wishes,
Jamie/RhodeRunner
</ChosenAnswer>
