<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Question>
<Subject>
How to train my puppy ?
</Subject>
<Content>
I have a 4 months Shih Tzu puppy. Recently I'm having trouble training him. 
He is kind of hate walking with leash, every time I put the leash on, he will try to bite it. And he is not following me when I was walking. I saw lots of videos about this, but actually it didn't help. Is there any way can let him know how to walk with leash ?
And every time he see some one he will rush to people and jump on them, doesn't listen to me. He is really excited about anybody he see. How to prevent this ? 
Last thing is every time I sit on a chair or something higher than him, he will try to jump on, if he can't, he will bark all the time until I let him get on, what should I do with this ?
Anyone have any suggestion? thank you very much.
</Content>
</Question>
<ChosenAnswer>
Hi, I am a dog trainer for 25 yrs. 

You need to purchase what is called a shoulder point harness. This type of harness goes around the dogs chest and legs and has a clip for the leash up on the back of the dog in middle of shoulder blades. This way, he cannot reach the leash to chew it. When he swivels his head to go for it anyway, tell him sharp "UH UH" gently correct him with a small tug and continue your walk. Do this repeatedly and frequently and he will learn to walk on a leash. 

Patience is the key here. He is a young pup and will learn over time and consistency in his training. And always, always train with love and positive methods- never hit or harshly scold. Never train out of fear. You want your dog to admire you as his pack leader, not fear you.

Good luck with your puppy! All the best.
</ChosenAnswer>
<Answers>
<Answer>
Put him in dog obedience school or call a professional dog trainer. :)
</Answer>
<Answer>
why dont you get some treats that he loves and only give him them when he does something right. or, as i saw on embarrassing pets on tv, get a clicker type thing and treats as well. try to train him to heel, which means to walk round you before he needs to go on a leash, and he may do that. or you could even spray some scented spray on the leash and he will go for the scent and probably, if you act quick enough, will stay on the leash.
</Answer>
</Answers>