<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Question>
<Subject>
Should all UK towns and their cafes or restaurants provide Halal food?
</Subject>
<Content>
Some friends of mine visited Dartmouth in Devon whilst on holiday last summer. They could not find any cafes or food shops that provided Halal prepared foods. Its important to their religion that they only consume Halal food. Even if you buy a cake in a bakers you can not be too what happens in the kitchen, for example the cake may have been sliced using a knife used for preparing ham.

Its simply not just a case of avoiding pork, alcohol and only being allowed to eat halal prepared meat, but the kitchen and its utensils should not have been used for prohibited foods.

Places like Dartmouth are supposed to be tourist towns and should provide foods for people of all religions. We all enjoy buying a snack when visiting a town or attraction while on holiday. Not everyone wants to bring packed lunch. Its not fair if some people have to go without buying food because no place will provide suitable food for them.

I think its only fair that nowadays every town should provide at least one halal cafe or restaurant and hopefully one day every British catering establishment will be halal.
</Content>
</Question>
<ChosenAnswer>
When I went to Bosnia, all the meat was Halal. I will not eat halal meat, so guess what, I opted for foods which weren't a meat dish, there were plenty of other options. 

I could not go to their country and demand they slaughter and sell an animal as meat the way I prefer to eat it. When you go to another country, you live by their way of life and their laws, if you don't like it, you know how to get back out the country (but I guess our benefits system is too much to throw away, huh).

Cafes and restaurants rarely use the same cutlery for different food groups anyway, they normally have blue for bakery items, red for cooked meat, brown for raw meat, etc - all for food preparation and hygiene policies.
</ChosenAnswer>
<Answers>
<Answer>
No.  To prevent animal cruelty, many countries forbid Halal and Kosher meat.  Switzerland is one, and the Netherlands are passing the same law.  It will become EU law in a couple of years.
</Answer>
<Answer>
We can't dictate what business wants to open where. If someone thinks there is a business opportunity then they will start opening halal only places.
</Answer>
</Answers>