<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Question>
<Subject>
Bearded dragon question...?
</Subject>
<Content>
I just bought a baby one yesterday. I have a basking spot lamp that says it is a double reflector that focuses 35% more light/heat and provides beneficial UVA rays important to the psycholical well-being of him. My question is does that mean it gives him not only the heat, but the "sun rays" he needs? I also was wondering how long should this light be on. The lady at pet smart said 4 hours, but on places on the net it says 10 to 12 hours. He's getting used to his new home, but hasn't eatin yet. I have bearded dragon juvenile food and freeze- dried crickets. Any advice would be greatly appreciated. Thank you for your time.
</Content>
</Question>
<ChosenAnswer>
Let me try to break this down as simply as I can: diurnal (active during the day time) reptiles like the bearded dragon require 3 types of "light," UVA, UVB, and heat. Any white light emitting light source will emit UVA, including heat bulbs, that's the easy one to provide for. UVB on the other hand can only be reproduced by a fluorescent source. UVB will always be a separate bulb from the heat lamp, unless you use a MVB (mercury vapor bulb) which is the only reptile use bulb that will emit both UVB and heat from one bulb. 

I highly recommend that you do not use coiled/compact UVB bulbs as they are known to cause severe eye damage and/or blindness in reptiles not to mention they have trouble maintaining UVB output over time. The long tube UVB bulbs are best, like Zoomed's Repsitun model: http://lllreptile.com/store/catalog/reptile-supplies/uvb-fluorescent-lights-mercury-vapor-bulbs/-/zoo-med-24-repti-sun-100-fluorescent-bulb/ Remember to replace UVB bulbs according to the manufacturers recommendation after which time the bulb will no longer produce UVB even if visible light still is. 

So, to answer your question, no, if you just have a bulb that says it produces UVA then you do not have "the sun's rays" that your bearded needs. You need to also provide a source a UVB lighting. 

The person at Petsmart is very wrong; in fact it is always a good idea to second guess what most pet store employees tell you; they don't have the best track record regarding giving reliable pet care info. UVB and basking temp (should be about 110 F for a baby, 95 F for an adult) should be available for 10 - 12 hours a day.  

Freeze dried food is not a good staple food source; you need to offer live feeder insects. Bearded dragons are sight hunters, they need to see the food move to trigger a feeding response, especially when they are babies. Live food is also higher in nutritional value than freeze dried. Crickets, silk worms, phoenix worms, and various feeder roaches, like red-lobster, turkistan, and dubia, are good example of staple insects to offer your bearded. Wax worms and meal worms should only be offered as treat items, for variety's sake. 

I would highly recommend that you read through some reliable bearded guides to make sure you have everything set up correctly: 

http://herp-info.webs.com/beardeddragon.htm

http://www.beardeddragon.org/articles/caresheet/?page=1
</ChosenAnswer>
<Answers>
<Answer>
mm it depends on the size of his tank or cage or whatever you have him in..atleast as far as i'm concerned.  if there are shady areas he can move to (for example a 3x5x4 tank with light on one side) then you can leave it on a full 12-14 hours, if its a small tank and he can't escape the light then 4-6 at most at a time though quite possibly 4-6 hours at a time twice a day.  either way you also need to keep an eye on the temperature if you are using a dry fish tank as UV lights in my experience up the temperature significantly and without proper ventilation it can become an oven.

as to what the light provides it gives UV rays..which is important for health in lizards as it is in humans.
</Answer>
<Answer>
That lady at PetSmart is a disgrace to the rest of us PetSmart associates... sheesh. Yes, it gives him the "sun rays" necessary, that's what UVA is. And it should be on 10-12 hours, just like the sun would be up for 10-12 hours in his natural environment. As for the heat, just be sure to use a thermometer.

Also, Beardies often do not eat food that is not moving, so its anyone's guess whether or not he'll touch the freeze-dried crickets or the processed food. I tell all my customers they can try it, but don't count on it. Also try green leafy veggies, like kale and spinach. 

Best of luck!
</Answer>
</Answers>