<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Question>
<Subject>
What to feed my dog after gastroenteritis?
</Subject>
<Content>
My dog has been sick for about 3 days now.  He has been having diarheya everywhere and he began to vomit lastnight.  I thought it would pass until he started to vomit blood and wouldnt drink any water.  I took him to the Animal Hospital and they ran blood work and everything came back normal. No pancreatitis or anything abnormal.  The vet said it was gastroenteritis and gave him fluids under his skin , an injection of nausea medication along with some take home antibiotics.  So my question is.. Is it normal for dogs to throw up blood while having gastroenteritis? and will these antibiotics help? I have tryed to give him water but he wont take it.. what should i do? i dont want him to get dehydrated and also should i try to give him a little bit of food?... Some help would be great. thank you :)
They didnt take x-rays they offered them but i just couldnt afford anymore treatment.  I feel like shit for saying that but after what they have done already i wont be buying grocerys for the next few weeks.  I will give them and call and see what they say.  Thank you for the help.
Ok so i spoke to the vet and he said the give him white rice and boiled chicken but only a little at a time.  Seince he recieved the fluids lastnight he said not to worry about drinking water for at least a couple of days.  I went home at lunch to check on him and he is doing 1000etter he was actually walkin around and wagin his tail :) thanks everbody for the info its greatly appreciated.
</Content>
</Question>
<ChosenAnswer>
To answer your questions in order:
1) It is not normal for dogs to be vomiting, much less to have blood in it.  However, if they have been vomiting numerous times, then the blood could be due to irritation of the stomach and intestines.  He could also have Parvovirus, a GI foreign body, or any number of things.  Did your vet take radiographs (x-rays)?
2) Your vet would not prescribe them if they didn't think it would be helpful.
3) If he shows no interest in water, then take him back to your vet.  It could be due to nausea or any number of things.  He could become severly dehydrated (especially if he continues to vomit and have diarrhea).  From there you end up with electrolyte imbalances, which can lead to heart and kidney problems.  And being dehydrated, vomiting, and having diarrhea just doesn't feel good.
4) Call your vet.  They should have discussed a bland diet with you, including the frequency of feeding and how much to feed at each sitting.

It sounds like your dog may benefit from being hospitalized, and put on IV fluids to help his hydration, administer the antibiotics IV, and to ensure that he starts to recover.  

You should ABSOLUTELY call your veterinarian back immediately to clarify anything you have questions about.  They have seen your pet, and are most aware of his condition.  No one online will be able to assist you more than your vet can.
</ChosenAnswer>
<Answers>
<Answer>
You need to ask your vet these questions.
</Answer>
<Answer>
Boiled WHITE rice and boiled chicken breast. Bland food. NO SPICES! 

My vet told me when a dog is vomiting a lot,  it could be a sign of obstruction. Did they do any x-rays? I don't know if vomiting blood is common with this ailment. 

You should call your vet now and ask them what is normal or not.
</Answer>
</Answers>