<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Question>
<Subject>
yoga and horses.....?
</Subject>
<Content>
I got a riding lesson today on one of my boss's fino horses and it made me realize just how unsteady my left leg is. I mentioned it to my boss and she said to start doing yoga. But there are just so many poses and programs! Any good poses or programs (I'm willing to buy a dvd as long as it is under $20) to help specifically with leg stabilization?
I just have a few issues supporting my back and my left leg flops. 
Because I don't feel like spending over $20 on a freakin DVD
</Content>
</Question>
<ChosenAnswer>
I also have back problems that transfer into my legs. I have done Yoga for riders for a while, a 20 minute routine I found on YouTube (I think its called "Yoga for horse back riding" hosted by a man) It helped with noticing slight differences in my balance and weight distribution but not really for the way I use my legs and back. 

Here is what I do now and it really helps....
When I first get on I take 1 leg and pull it back up to touch my butt with my heel and hold it there for 1 lap at a walk around a large dressage arena. Then the same thing with the other leg. 
Then 1 lap at a walk around the arena with both my legs pulled out as far as I can, so they are not touching the saddle. 
Then a lap doing scissors, one leg forward as far as I can and the other back, then switch legs. 
I'll also trot doing, down 2 beats, up one for a wile, then up 2 down 1 making sure the weight is going into the balls of my feet. If the weight is going into your heels (it throws your leg forward) put the stirrups up against the heel of your boot. Do a nice working trot, not a slow trot. 
All this will help you use both legs evenly, keep proper contact and use your wight correctly, to keep your leg in a good position. BTW you dont want your leg locked in place, it will move WITH the horse a bit. 

When I first started doing it I'd do it every day. Now I just do it once or twice a week or as needed. Now not only is my leg better, but my back is relaxing.
</ChosenAnswer>
<Answers>
<Answer>
what are you having problems with?
i wouldn't bother with yoga i'd practice more with riding and fixing my problem, ride bareback, with no irons, theres also a way to ride on your knees? that help alot with your thigh muscles (bareback though)
ya i really wouldn't bother with the yoga
maybe a back brase will help, sometimes my back really gets to me and i've thought about getting one.
with your leg flopping, just try putting all your weight in your heel and hangon with only your legs, holding my leg back helps me with flopping the more it's forward the more it flops :/ work your calf muscles, maybe try standing on the edge of your steps (on the ball of your foot) and balance to strengthen those muscles
</Answer>
<Answer>
You don't want to spend more than $20 and yet you have an expensive hobby like riding horses? 
I really can't help you.
</Answer>
</Answers>