<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Question>
<Subject>
When is the best time to travel to Ireland?
</Subject>
<Content>
My sister and I would like to go to Ireland. I graduate in the spring, and so we'd like to go between then and winter. We don't want too many tourists, and since we'll both be out of school we can go anytime between the middle of June to early November. We don't want it to be too cold (not sure when exactly there fall is... or what the weather is really like there during our autumn months), but we don't feel like we need to go right in the middle of summer either. We're both in our early 20s and just wanting to explore the beautiful country while we're still young and before our lives start to get even crazier! Can anyone give me an idea of when the best time for us to go to Ireland would be?
</Content>
</Question>
<ChosenAnswer>
People do not go to Ireland on holiday for the weather, it is unpredictable.  One thing you can be sure of about Irish weather is how little you can be sure of. It may be shirtsleeves and sunglasses in February, but winter woollies in March and even during the summer. 

And then there’s the rain. Ireland receives a lot of rain, with certain areas getting a soaking as many as 270 days of the year. County Kerry is the worst affected. The southeast is the driest, enjoying a more continental climate.

The Irish weather works on the ‘four seasons in a day’ principle, which basic­ally means that you can’t predict a thing when it comes to the behaviour of the sky. Some basic assumptions, however, can be made. 

In summer, from May to July, the days are reasonably warm and – most importantly – very long: at the height of summer you won’t need to turn on lights until after 10pm. It is also peak tourist season, which means there are far more people just about everywhere but the most remote corners of the island, and prices are at their highest. Not surprisingly, most of the yearly festivals occur during these times so as to take advantage of the crowds and the more favourable weather.

Spring (February to April) and Autumn (August to October) make good alternatives, although the country’s ever-growing popularity as a tourist destination can often blur the lines between mid- and high-season tourism. Still, you have a better chance of some peace and quiet, and the weather can be surprisingly better in April and September than in mid-July – again, it’s all part of the uncertainty principle. Spring festivities include the ever-popular St Patrick’s Festival.

Although temperatures do not often venture below freezing, winter (December to February) can be brutal, for huge parts of the country – the west and northwest in particular.  Crowds are at their thinnest, but many of the country’s tourist attractions and services close down in October and don’t reopen until Easter, which paradoxically leaves visitors with a more convincing taste of how Ireland is experienced by most of the Irish: it’s cold, grey and dark by 5pm, but there’s always a pub to escape into when the rain starts sheeting down. 

The thing to do is to bring the right clothing with you, clothes so you can layer up if it is cold and take off layers when it warms up.  Waterproof clothing and footwear are essential plus an umbrella..  As that famous Scotsman Billy Connolly says "there is no such thing as bad weather just the wrong clothes"

Afraid I cannot be more helpful, it is really a case of pot luck, although as the weather is so changeable often a cold wet morning will turn into a lovely warm sunny afternoon and evening or visa versa.
</ChosenAnswer>
<Answers>
<Answer>
If you mean the Republic of Ireland (Dublin) then anytime.  The summer there is much more mild than most of the US (are you coming from the US?).  Their seasons are the same as all the countries in the Northern Hemisphere but I would suggest fall.  It does get pretty cold in Ireland so going before winter is your best bet.  September for example.  Rent a car and spend a couple days outside of Dublin seeing the countryside and you will have the trip of a lifetime.
</Answer>
<Answer>
To explore the beautiful countryside you will need to be old enough to hire a car because public transport is expensive & only goes as far as the main towns/cities, most rural places don't have a bus or train service. You could stay in a city & get a bus tour to say the Cliffs of Moher or Dingle peninsula but you will be with all the other tourists. By definition most tourists will go to the best places so you might have to put up with a few tourists along the way. 

Best weather the past couple of years has been around late April - late May but it can pour with rain for days on end at any time of the year so be prepared with waterproof jackets/boots etc. We only had a few sunny days this summer, barely 24C on a few occasions, more like 14C most days. We used our BBQ on precisely 4 occasions. Autumn is from mid August onwards as far as the weather goes if not officially according to the calender. The days start to shorten & it gets even wetter, windier & colder. We had frosts in October so I wouldn't advise visiting late in the year to be honest, Spring time is your best bet.

You do realise it is quite expensive to visit Ireland? You are going to need a few thousand dollars saved up for flights, insurance, food, accommodation & spending money. Eating out in particular is quite expensive compared to America I believe.
</Answer>
</Answers>
