<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Question>
<Subject>
I took some photos of my model girlfriend with my Nikon D7000. What do you think of these photos?
</Subject>
<Content>
http://i.imgur.com/S2MD2.jpg http://i.imgur.com/T2zff.jpg http://i.imgur.com/Xytex.jpg I took some photos of my model girlfriend with my Nikon D7000 (see links above). What do you think of these photos? The lighting was not the best, but the pics turned out ok in my opinion.
</Content>
</Question>
<ChosenAnswer>
</ChosenAnswer>
<Answers>
<Answer>
deleting a question where you dont like the answer won't get you better answers... i refer to my previous answer: 

you need to learn about white balance, composition, angle, and work on using the camera properly...

[edit - and she most be very new to modeling, because she does look unsure of her poses)
</Answer>
<Answer>
lol, he has posted this so many times today already.clearly hes mad that people know he took her pic off the net and it's NOT his gf
</Answer>
<Answer>
Not bad, but too many distracting elements for my taste.  For example: 

In the photo on the couch, the pillow she is resting on clashes with everything else in the shot.  There are also some distracting background elements like the light fixture and what looks like a door handle on the left.  In the standing photo (from the front) there is a corner of a rug creeping in, some kind of box in the lower right corner and what looks like a power cord.  In the shot from the back, the crumpled bottom of the curtain is pretty noticeable as well as the power outlet.  Compositionally, this one is not my favorite, I would suggest trying a different crop because I dont think cutting her off at the calf looks great. I do like the shadow, though.

My suggestion is to pay close attention to what's going on in the background and if possible, stand on a chair, get on the ground, do whatever you need to do to get rid of distracting elements.  Using a fairly wide aperture is also helpful in blurring out unwanted background elements.  I've had a few great shots ruined myself because there was something in the background I didn't notice at first.
</Answer>
</Answers>
