<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Question>
<Subject>
melting brass did not work?
</Subject>
<Content>
my friends and I are trying to melt bras to make some little figures.  we have made a furnace as such, we took a clay flower pot with a hole in the bottom put a piece of steel pipe in the middle of it with a cap on the bottom, filled the pipe with brass scrap, surounded the pipe with charcoal lit it off and pumped air through the hole in the pot, everything got red hot but did not melt. what am I doing wrong
</Content>
</Question>
<ChosenAnswer>
I would recommend to start with something more simple like tin, pewter, aluminum or zinc, they all have a much more reasonable melting point. 

I'll just echo both other answers.  Molten brass is damn hot and usually it's pressurized gas and forced air or oxygen.  Even if you did melt it, I doubt you foresaw the issues of handling it and pouring it.  It's really too advanced for a beginner, both in tooling and safety.  Just the zinc fumes will get you, if you don't take precautions.  Pewter is perfect for what you are doing, and it melts on a stove top.
</ChosenAnswer>
<Answers>
<Answer>
I would recommend to start with something more simple like tin, pewter, aluminum or zinc, they all have a much more reasonable melting point. Brass has an even higher melting point than bronze and I would think your charcoal just doesn't get hot enough. I bet you also did take charcoal as it is used for barbecue which does not get as hot as real coal (e.g. for blacksmithing one needs coal, not barbecue charcoal). 

I have done a fair amount of metal casting, but never tried to build my own furnace, but I think your version is just too small and doesn't get hot enough. I have melted small amounts of bronze in a crucible with a large propane torch (much larger than the plumbers torch, but it can be run of those propane cylinders you can buy for a gas grill).
</Answer>
<Answer>
I melt brass and cast it http://www.mikegigi.com/castgobl.htm
Brass melts at just under 2000F which is a bright yellow heat, not red hot.  http://www.mikegigi.com/techspec.htm#SELCTEMP
You might be able to make a version of your setup work, but it would take quite a bit of charcoal and a lot of forced air.  I use propane with a blower and a burner I built  http://www.mikegigi.com/meltmetl.htm and http://www.mikegigi.com/firehole.htm
</Answer>
</Answers>
