<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Question>
<Subject>
I just adopted a 2 year old male German Shepherd with Major bad behaviors?
</Subject>
<Content>
Last night, I adopted a 2 year old Male German Shepherd. (He is 92 pounds) He does not listen to any commands, but my major problem is that he will not go outside on command, or even with me. I will walk outside and he will stand at the door and stare at me or run away. My other MAJOR problem is that he will not get in his crate. I will get a treat and try to get him in there that way, it wont work. He wont even get close to the crate. If I come towards him, he will run away. How do I train him to feel comfortable in his crate? and to willingly go outside...and to come on command. He wont do anything on command. Its very frustrating.
I have a 9 month old German Shepherd that I raised from a puppy. I trained her myself. She is crate trained, potty trained, and can sit, lay down, stay, come, fetch, and will even stay in a down position while I throw a treat across the floor or even right next to her paw, and she wont get it until I give her the command. Yes, lots of time and lots of patients...I just dont know how to do it with a grown dog. She tosses me around like its nothing!...but basically, what I do is the same thing I did with my puppy...lots of patience, lots of time, lots of praise, lots of treats, and lots of repition....Right? Is there any tricks I could use? 
</Content>
</Question>
<ChosenAnswer>
</ChosenAnswer>
<Answers>
<Answer>
Maybe get a book on training. You have to be in command at all times. There are ways to get your new dog used to the crate or going out. I would start with a leash. Put the leash on the dog and just walk around the crate a few times. Then take the leash off and do nothing else but that. Later do it again. When the dog is ok with this, then open the door and walk around the crate, leave the door open all the time. Put something fun inside. Let your dog go in when he wants to for no reason. Do not shut the door. Let him walk in and out for a few days. At some point he will feel ok with this and you can then close the door but not for long at all. Open the door and let him out and see how he acts. If you push it, it will never work. With going outside, put the leash on and just take him for a walk. He will learn to really like this. Potty outside will come at some point.
</Answer>
<Answer>
Try obedience classes.  Have patience with him, you just got him and who knows how he was treated before you brought him home.
</Answer>
</Answers>